<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: group_listen | blog.amuzz.in]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/categories/group-listen/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-03T00:22:05+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://blog.amuzz.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[amuzzin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Group Listen - the missing feature in the music world]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/2014/04/03/group-listen-the-missing-feature-in-the-music-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-03T00:18:49+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/2014/04/03/group-listen-the-missing-feature-in-the-music-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>How is amuzzin different?</h4>

<p>We have spent more than a year building the necessary features for a complete Music listening experience but the question we frequently faced is, how different is amuzzin from the rest of the music streaming websites available in Internet.</p>

<p>We tried binding social experience to the music world previously to some extent with a feature called <strong>Friends' Stream</strong>. This time we have tried making a giant leap by introducing a new feature called <strong>Group Listen</strong>.</p>

<h4>How does it work</h4>

<p>Group Listen works just like a conference call. Instead of you speaking with friends in a conference, you listen to a common queue along with your friends, synced in realtime.</p>

<h3>How to enter Group Listen</h3>

<p>You can enter into Group Listen in two ways:</p>

<h5>1. Starting a New Group Listen</h5>

<ul>
<li>Start Group Listen by clicking <strong>Group Listen</strong> tab at side menu and by clicking the <strong>[Start Group Listen]</strong> button.</li>
<li>Add Online friends by clicking <strong>[+]</strong> button near each friend.</li>
</ul>


<h5>2. Enter existing Group Listen</h5>

<ul>
<li>If your friend has already started a Group Listen he can add you to the Group by clicking <strong>[+]</strong> button near your name.</li>
<li>You will get a request on your screen.</li>
<li>You can either Accept or Reject the group listen request.</li>
</ul>


<h4>I entered Group Listen and I lost my Current Queue</h4>

<p>Don&rsquo;t worry your queue is safe with us. Whenever you are bored of the Group or you want to step back and take control, you can click <strong>[Leave Group]</strong>. You will get back your Current Queue again.</p>

<h4>What can happen in Group Listen ?</h4>

<ul>
<li>Whatever song your friends starts listening to, will get reflected to you and the Group members.</li>
<li>You can chat within the group.</li>
<li>Add any of your online friends to the Group.</li>
<li>Leave the Group and enjoy the songs independently if you hate that Group.</li>
<li>Start a new Group and add your loved ones.</li>
</ul>


<p>You can enjoy the feature from here:
<a href="http://amuzz.in/group_listen">http://amuzz.in/group_listen</a></p>

<p>Regards,</p>

<p>Amuzzin Team</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
