<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: feedback | blog.amuzz.in]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/categories/feedback/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-28T00:31:25+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://blog.amuzz.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[amuzzin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[publishing song made easy in amuzzin]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/2014/01/28/publishing-song-made-easy-in-amuzzin/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-28T00:23:23+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/2014/01/28/publishing-song-made-easy-in-amuzzin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Publishing songs made easy with amuzzin</h1>

<p>We received few requests from budding artists on their need to upload their own Album Art and to edit the language, genre and lyrics of their song. We are glad we completed those features in the current release (28 Jan 2014).</p>

<h4>Pictures, pictures everywhere!</h4>

<p>Whenever we display your song in amuzzin, mostly it would result in displaying an boring <strong>&ldquo;No Image Available&rdquo;</strong> frame. This might happen because, your songs might lack an Album Art internally as specified by mp3 format.</p>

<p>We know pictures plays very important role in this multimedia era and it&rsquo;s more descriptive than any other form of media. If you got a perfect Album Art for your song, you are going to attract more music fans than your fellow artists.</p>

<h4>So how do I update my songs' Album Art?</h4>

<p>Very simple! Go to <strong>My Songs</strong> and click edit Icon on the appropriate song (now edit option appears on top right corner of each song). It would display three column page.</p>

<p>In the first column you would be viewing the old Album Art.</p>

<p>You can upload an album art in two ways:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you have your Album Art in your PC then click <strong>choose file</strong>, locate your image file and upload it.</li>
<li>If you have an url which points your Album Art then copy paste the Remote Url in the appropriate field and click <strong>Save Song</strong>.</li>
</ul>


<p>The new album art would automatically reflect in every other place it has been published in amuzzin.</p>

<h4>More details on your song, more popular you are in amuzzin</h4>

<p>So you changed your Song with a nice Album Art, but more details about your song would help your Music fans find you in their search more easily.</p>

<p>In the second column you can Edit the Genre,Language,Year. You can add complete <strong>Lyrics</strong> of the Song which might help the next level music listeners who would listen music along with the lyrics of the song.</p>

<h4>I am an artist and I need my profile WITH MY PHOTO</h4>

<p>Previously there is no way in amuzzin to edit your Profile photo. We have either extracted your photo from Facebook or from Gravatar.</p>

<p>&lsquo;coz we thought amuzzin would be more of adding new music by an artist, than updating their profile every hour with a photo which they might have took on the parkside (ofcourse with vintage filter applied).</p>

<p>But since few artists are confused about changing their identity in Gravatar or Facebook services we decided to allow <strong>Edit Profile Photo</strong> within amuzzin, from where they can update their profile photo.</p>

<p>This would appear on either viewing your own Profile or clicking on the Dropdown at top right corner.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 reasons why you should own an amuzzin account]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/2014/01/18/5-reasons-why-you-should-own-an-amuzzin-account/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T23:04:25+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.amuzz.in/blog/2014/01/18/5-reasons-why-you-should-own-an-amuzzin-account</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>5 reasons why you should own an amuzzin account</h1>

<p>We have officially launched amuzzin three days ago and we have few <strong>genuine</strong> users. We are really happy for their adventurous dive into our application, exploring each and every feature and providing us their valuble suggestions. Some suggestions are way beyond our scope, but we will get there :)</p>

<p>We would like to draw a clear line of what is not amuzzin before we start.</p>

<h4>amuzzin is a complete music repository</h4>

<p><strong>No.</strong> If you search for your favourite song and if the search returns nothing please don’t get dissapointed. amuzzin is a user driven model wherein one user uploads one&rsquo;s creation and rest gets access to it. Someday the song you searched for might be uploaded to amuzzin by its creator. So keep checking!</p>

<h4>amuzzin is yet another online music player</h4>

<p><strong>No.</strong> It is personalized and tailored for you, depending on your taste. It provides <strong>realtime</strong> updates on your uploaded song from all your friends. It also provides realtime music feed on your friends activities. So you stay tuned to them, with your tune playing.</p>

<h2>why you should have an amuzzin account</h2>

<h5>1. You might miss what your friends are currently playing</h5>

<blockquote><p>No friends, No fun.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is the main inspiration behind amuzzin. A song in isolation is just a variation in amplitude and frequencies (and all other technical parameters to add on). When we hear some song we love, we recall a situation or a person or some external real life parameter which completes it. Most of the times it would be our <strong>friends</strong>.</p>

<p>We had several crappy ways in past like:</p>

<ul>
<li>Link Gtalk status to some music players (in worst case  changing it manually)</li>
<li>Spam people on Facebook with &lsquo;Listening to&rsquo; statuses</li>
<li>Tweet each and every song you play using #nowplaying</li>
</ul>


<p>This is how the world worked atleast for letting your friends know what you are currently listening to (which would annoy rest of the crowd).</p>

<p>We have a feature in amuzzin called <strong>friends' stream</strong> which would list all your online friends, their currently playing songs and their entire Queue of Now Playing.</p>

<p>Whenever you signin using Facebook we sync all your facebook friends who are in amuzzin database. If you want to keep your facebook world out of the amuzzin world (since both serves entirely different purposes) you can manually search your close ones and add them selectively.</p>

<p>You can block anyone from friends' stream who might be a <strong>friend of a friend of a friend</strong> whom you accepted in Facebook accidentally and you don&rsquo;t wish to see in the friends' stream, by searching their name and clicking <strong>&lsquo;Hide from Stream&rsquo;</strong>.</p>

<p> Explore this feature from here: <a href="http://amuzz.in/friends">http://amuzz.in/friends</a></p>

<h5>2. Add once, Play anywhere</h5>

<blockquote><p>Copying and syncing is always pain. Let amuzzin handle that.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you are like me, switching between PC&rsquo;s and laptops in Home and using a different system in Office you could organize it onetime and just login to <a href="http://amuzz.in">http://amuzz.in</a> from elsewhere.</p>

<h5>3. You can upload your songs and promote it to a wide user base</h5>

<blockquote><p>We are pleased to be the startup Board for your Music Career</p></blockquote>

<p>If you are a singer or a musician and would like to broadcast your talent to the entire world (atleast to the amuzzin circle) this would the right place. Upload your song and keep track of Favourites, Comments, ratings etc., on your song after uploading. You can click <strong>Upload Songs</strong> anytime and upload the songs.</p>

<p> Explore this feature from here: <a href="http://amuzz.in/upload">http://amuzz.in/upload</a></p>

<h5>4. You might miss whats happening around your friends circle</h5>

<blockquote><p>We are not replicating facebook. We are doing what is necessary for a music lover.</p></blockquote>

<p>We know the world is asynchronous, with different friends in different timezones. List of all the activities by your friends would appear as a timeline. We didn&rsquo;t try to replicate facebook, but when we completed this feature they resembled like twin sisters, Where one displays the whole list of craps while other displays the feeds specific about music. We have this organized in a feature called <strong>music feed</strong>.</p>

<p> Explore this feature from here: <a href="http://amuzz.in/activities">http://amuzz.in/activities</a></p>

<h5>5. You might miss the songs which you would love</h5>

<blockquote><p>Algorithms are good slave but bad masters.</p></blockquote>

<p>We have tried algorithms to recommend the songs you would love but you haven&rsquo;t heard, depending on the Pitch,Frequency,Artist,Album,Users and all other details available about the song in match with you. This is still in alpha but we think this might help you explore more songs and will keep you happy always with diverse songs from our repository. We know algorithms are bad atleast in two things, deciding your music and your partner. We just provide you a path to explore new songs here, like a pinch of salt in your entire music dish.</p>

<p> Explore this feature from here: <a href="http://amuzz.in/home">http://amuzz.in/home</a></p>

<p><code>P.S:</code> Our initial assumptions while building this platform might be wrong, because it could be heavily biased by our friends view. Please feel free to comment or provide your suggestions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
